What you guys don't understand is...
男生不了解
...for us, kissing is as important as any part of it.
对我们来说 接吻跟其他部分一样重要
Yeah, right.
对，没错
You serious?
真的吗？
Oh, yeah.
对
Everything you need to know is in that first kiss.
初吻能告诉你所有答案
- Absolutely. - Yeah, I think, for us...
- 没错 - 我想对我们来说
...kissing is pretty much like an opening act.
接吻只是开场
I mean, it's like the stand-up comedian you have to sit through...
像是你得忍受搞笑艺人那一段
...before Pink Floyd comes out.
才能等到《平克·佛洛伊德》登场
Yeah, and it's not that we don't like the comedian.
对，我们不是不喜欢搞笑艺人
It's just that that's not...
但那不是…
...why we bought the ticket.
我们买票想看的表演
See, the problem is, though...
听着，问题是
...after the concert's over, no matter how great the show was...
演唱会结束复，不论表演有多棒
...you girls are always looking for the comedian again.
女生还在找搞笑艺人
I mean, we're in the car, we're fighting traffic...
我是说我们在车里，对抗塞车
...basically just trying to stay awake.
努力保持清醒
Yeah, well, word of advice: Bring back the comedian.
对，听我的建议 把搞笑艺人找回来
Otherwise, you're gonna find yourself...
不然你会发现自己
...sitting at home listening to that album alone.
一个人坐在家里听专辑
Are we still talking about sex?
我们还在讨论性爱吗？
Friends S01E02: The One with the Sonogram at the End
《老友记》 第一季 第2集：超声波检查
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
（史前历史博物馆）
ROSS: No, it's good. It is good.
不，真的很不错
It's just that, doesn't she seem a little angry?
你不觉得她看起来有点愤怒吗？
Well, she has issues.
她有问题
（制片：塔德·史帝文斯）
Does she?
是吗？
He's out banging other women over the head with a club...
他跑出去跟别的女人胡搞
...while she sits at home trying to get the mastodon smell out of the carpet.
她待在家里 想除掉地毯上乳齿象的味道
Marsha, see, these are cave people.
玛莎，他们是原始人
Okay, they have issues like:
好吧，这才是他们的问题
"Gee, that glacier's getting kind of close." See?
〝天啊，冰河距离有点近〞 懂吗？
Speaking of issues, isn't that your ex-wife?
说到问题，那不是你的前妻吗？
- No, no. - Yes, it is. Carol, hi.
- 不 - 没错，卡萝
ROSS: Okay. Yes. Yes, it is.
对，没错
How about I'll catch up with you in the Ice Age?
我们何不等到冰河时期再谈？
（即将开幕，史前生活展）
（编剧：玛莎·卡夫曼  大卫·肯蓝）
（导演：詹姆斯·柏洛斯）
- Hi. - Hi.
- 嗨 - 嗨
So...
好吧
You look great.
你看起来很不错
I hate that.
我讨厌那样
Sorry. Thanks. You look good too.
抱歉，谢谢，你看起来也很不错
Well, you know, in here, anyone who...
在这里所有可以…
...stands erect...
直立的人…
- So, what's new? Still a... - A lesbian?
- 怎么样？你还是… - 女同志？
Well...
好吧
You never know.
这种事谁都说不准
How's, um...? How's the family?
你家人还好吧？
Marty's still totally paranoid.
玛蒂的疑心病还是很重
- Oh, and... - Carol, why are you here, Carol?
- 还有… - 卡萝，你来这里做什么？
- I'm pregnant. - Pregnant.
- 我怀孕了 - 怀孕？
Oh. Looks like she didn't leave in such a hurry after all.
看起来她不急着离开
I think this is the episode of Three's Company...
我想这一集的《三人行》
...where's there's some kind of misunderstanding.
发生了一点误会
Then I've already seen this one.
我看过这一集了
Are you through with that? Thanks.
你喝完了吗？谢谢
Yeah, sorry, the swallowing slowed me down.
抱歉，狼吞虎咽害我速度变慢
Whose little ball of paper is this?
这是谁的纸团？
Oh, that would be mine.
那应该是我的
See, I wrote a note to myself, then I didn't need it.
我写字条给自己，后来又不需要
So I balled it up and now I wish I was dead.
我把它揉成纸团 现在我真的很想死
She already fluffed that pillow. Monica, you know, you already fluffed...
她已经拍过靠枕了 摩妮卡，你已经拍过…
But it's fine.
没关系的
Look, I'm sorry.
听着，抱歉
I don't want to give them any more ammunition than they have.
我不想给他们能攻击我的地方
Yes, we know how cruel a parent can be...
对，我们知道父母会多么挑剔
...about the flatness of a child's pillow.
小孩家的靠枕太扁了
Monica? Hi. Um...
摩妮卡
Monica, um, you're scaring me.
摩妮卡，你吓到我了
I mean, you're, like, all chaotic and twirly, you know?
你神经兮兮的，非常可怕
Not in a good way.
那不是件好事
Yeah, calm down.
对，冷静下来
You don't see Ross getting all chaotic and twirly every time they come.
每次他们来这里，你不会看到罗斯 神经兮兮的，非常可怕
That's because, as far as my parents are concerned, Ross can do no wrong.
那是因为我爸妈认为 罗斯绝不会犯错
You see, he's the prince.
他是我们家的王子
Apparently they had some big ceremony before I was born.
显然我出生前 他们举行过非常重要的仪式
Ew, ew, ew.
呃 呃 呃
- What? - Ugly Naked Guy got a ThighMaster.
- 什么？ - 丑裸男在用瘦腿器
Ew.
呕
- Has anybody seen my engagement ring? - Yeah, it's beautiful.
- 谁看到我的订婚戒指了？ - 对，它真的很漂亮
Oh, God. Oh, God.
天啊
- Oh, God, oh, God, oh, God. - No, don't touch that.
- 天啊 - 不，别碰那个
Oh, like I wasn't dreading tomorrow enough having to give it back to him.
我很气明天得把它还给他
"Hi, Barry, remember me? I'm the girl...
贝瑞，记得我吗？ 我是在你家人面前
...that stomped on your heart in front of your entire family"
伤了你心的女孩
Oh, God. Now I'm gonna have to return the ring, without the ring...
天啊，现在我得归还戒指 戒指却不见了
...which makes it so much harder.
那让情况变得更复杂
Easy, Rach, we'll find it. Won't we?
别紧张，瑞秋 我们会找到它的，对吧？
- Oh, yeah. MONICA: Okay, look.
- 对 - 好吧，听着
When did you have it on last?
你最后一次戴上它 是什么时候的事？
Doy. Probably right before she lost it.
或许就在她把它弄丢之前
You don't get a lot of "doy" these days.
现在的人很难开得起玩笑
I know I had it this morning.
我知道今天早上我还戴着它
I know I had it when I was in the kitchen with...
我知道我在厨房里还戴着它
Dinah?
在晚餐里？
Oh, don't be mad.
别生气
- You didn't. - Oh, I'm sorry.
- 不可能 - 对不起
I gave you one job.
我交代你做一件事
Oh, but look how straight those noodles are.
看看那些面条有多直
Monica, you know that's not how you look for an engagement ring in a lasagna.
摩妮卡，那样子无法在千层面里 找到订婚戒指的
I just can't do it.
我没办法那么做
Boys?
兄弟们
We're going in.
轮到我们上了
Hi.
嗨
Oh, that is not a happy "hi."
你似乎不太开心
Carol's pregnant.
卡萝怀孕了
Oh, I found it.
我找到了
Well, what...? What?
什么？
Yeah.
对
Do that for another two hours...
再多撑个两小时
...you might be where I am right about now.
你的处境会跟我一样
Kind of puts that whole pillow thing in perspective, huh, Mon?
原来靠枕有那个功能，摩妮卡
Well, now, how do you fit into this whole thing?
你打算怎么办？
Well, Carol says she and Susan want me to be involved.
卡萝说她跟苏珊都希望我能参与
But if I'm not comfortable with it, I don't have to be involved.
如果我觉得为难也可以不参与
Basically, it's totally up to me.
基本上由我来决定
She is so great. I miss her.
她太棒了，我想念她
What does she mean by "involved"?
她说的参与是什么意思？
I mean, presumably, the biggest part of your job is done.
我想你完成最重要的工作了
Anyway, they want me to go down to this...
她们要我明天
...sonogram thing with them tomorrow.
陪她们去做超声波检查
So, what are you gonna do?
你打算怎么办？
I have no idea.
我不知道
No matter what I do, though, I'm still gonna be a father.
不论我怎么做，我还是要当爸爸了
Well, this is still ruined, right?
千层面已经毁了，对吧？
Oh. Martha Lugwin's daughter is gonna call you.
玛莎路格温的女儿要打电话给你
Mm. What's that curry taste?
那是什么咖喱的味道？
Curry.
就是咖喱
Mm.
唔
I think they're great. I really do.
我觉得很棒，真的
You remember the Lugwins?
还记得路格温家吧？
The big one had a thing for you, didn't she?
大女儿曾暗恋你，对吧？
They all had a thing for him.
她们都暗恋他
Oh, Mom.
妈
I'm sorry. Why is this girl going to call me?
对不起 这个女孩为什么要打电话给我？
Oh, she just graduated, and she wants to be something in cooking or food...
她刚毕业 想在餐饮界或食品界做事
...or I don't know.
我不知道
Anyway, I told her you had a restaurant, so...
总之我跟她说你开了一家餐厅
No, Mom. I don't have a restaurant. I work in a restaurant.
不，妈，我没有开餐厅 我在赛厅里工作
Well, they don't have to know that.
他们不必知道那么多
Ross, could you come and help me with the spaghetti.
罗斯，麻烦你过来帮我弄意大利面
Yes.
好的
Oh, we're having spaghetti. That's...
我们要吃意大利面，那真是…
...easy.
太轻松了
I know this is going to sound unbelievably selfish on my part...
我知道听起来我真的很自和
...but were you planning on bringing up the whole baby/lesbian thing?
你打算提起宝宝跟女同志的事吗？
Because I think it might take some of the heat off me.
我想那能帮我挡些子弹
What that Rachel did to her life. We ran into her parents at the club.
瑞秋打算怎么过生活？ 我们在俱乐部遇到她爸妈
They were not playing very well.
他们似乎很难过
I'm not gonna tell you what they spent on that wedding...
我不想告诉你们 他们花了多少钱办婚礼
...but $40,000 is a lot of money.
但四万块是一大笔钱
Well, at least she had the chance to leave a man at the altar.
至少她有机会在婚礼上甩了男人
- What's that supposed to mean? - Nothing.
- 那是什么意思？ - 没事
- It's an expression. - No, it's not.
- 那只是一种说法 - 不，不是的
Don't listen to your mother.
别听你妈的
You're independent and you always have been.
你很独立 你一直都是如此
Even when you were a kid, and you were chubby...
即使你小时候胖嘟嘟的
...and you had no friends, you were just fine.
没有朋友，你还是过得很好
You'd read alone in your room. And your puzzles...
你一个人在房里看书玩拼图
Look, there are people, like Ross, who need to shoot for the stars.
听着，像罗斯这样的人 必须追求成功
With his museum and his papers getting published.
他到博物馆工作，准备出版论文
Other people are satisfied with staying where they are.
其他人则是安于现状
I'm telling you, these are the people who never get cancer.
我要说的是这些人永远不会得癌症
And I read about these women trying to have it all, and I thank God...
我看到报道说这些女人想那么做 谢天谢地
...our little Harmonica doesn't seem to have that problem.
我们的小摩妮卡没有那样的问题
So, Ross, what's going on with you?
罗斯，你还好吗？
Any stories? No news, no little anecdotes to share with the folks?
有任何故事吗？ 没有消息或趣事要跟父母分享？
Okay, okay.
好吧
Ahem. Look, I, uh... I realize you guys have been wondering...
听着，我知道你们一直很好奇
...what exactly happened between Carol and me.
我跟卡萝到底是怎么了？
And so, well, here's the deal.
情况是这样的
Carol's a lesbian.
卡萝是女同志
She's living with a woman named Susan.
她跟一个叫苏珊的女人住在一起
She's pregnant with my child.
她怀了我的孩子
And she and Susan are going to raise the baby.
她跟苏珊要一起抚养孩子
And you knew about this?
你早就知道了？
（中央咖啡厅）
Your folks are really that bad, huh?
你们的爸妈真的有那么超过？
Well, you know, these people are pros.
他们可是专家
They know what they're doing. They take their time.
他们知道自己在做什么 愿意花时间
They get the job done.
不做完誓不甘休
Boy, I know they say that you can't change your parents.
天啊，我知道俗话说 人是无法换父母的
Boy, if you could, I'd want yours.
天啊，如果可以的话 我想跟你换父母
Must pee.
我得去尿尿
You know, it's even worse when you're twins.
这比你们是双胞胎还糟糕
- You're a twin? - Oh, yeah. We don't speak.
- 你是双胞胎？ - 对，我们不说话
She's like this high-powered, driven, career-type.
她是位高权重的霸道女强人
- What does she do? - She's a waitress.
- 她做什么样的工作？ - 她是服务生
All right. You guys, I kind of gotta clean up now.
好了，各位，我必须打扫
Chandler, you're an only child, right? You don't have any of this.
钱德，你是独生子 你不必忍受这一切
Well, no, although I did have an imaginary friend...
不，但我有个幻想的朋友
...who my parents actually preferred.
我爸妈比较喜欢他
RACHEL: Hit the lights, please.
请关灯
How long was I in there?
我在厕所持了多久？
I'm just cleaning up.
我只是在打扫
Oh, do you, uh...? Do you need any help?
你需要帮忙吗？
Um, okay, sure. Thanks.
当然，谢谢
Anyway...
总之…
So you nervous about Barry tomorrow?
你很紧张明天要跟贝瑞见面？
- Oh, a little. - Mm-hm.
有一点
- A lot. - Mm-hm.
非常紧张
So got any advice?
你有任何建议吗？
You know, as someone who's recently been dumped.
毕竟你有被甩的经验
Well, you may want to steer clear of the word "dumped."
你该避免用〝甩〞这个字
Chances are he's going to be this broken shell of a man. You know?
他很可能心都碎了，你懂吗？
So you should try not to look too terrific. I know it'll be hard.
你不能看起来太漂亮 我知道那很难
Or, you know, hey, I'll go down there, and I'll give Barry back his ring.
或是由我过去把戒指还给贝瑞
And you can go with Carol and Susan to the OB-GYN.
你陪卡萝跟苏珊去看妇产科
You've got Carol tomorrow.
明天你得去陪卡萝
When did it get so complicated?
何时世界变得这么复杂？
Got me.
你问倒我了
- Remember when we were in high school? - Yeah.
- 还记得我们念高中的时候吗？ - 对
I mean, didn't you think you' were gonna meet someone...
你不觉得你会遇上某人
...fall in love, and that'd be it?
坠入爱河，就这样过了一生吗？
- Ross? - Yes, yes.
- 罗斯 - 没错
Oh. Man. I never thought I'd be here.
天啊，我没想到我会落到这步田地
Me neither.
我也是
Hi. Sorry I'm late. I got stuck at work.
抱歉我迟到了，我有工作在忙
There was this big dinosaur thing. Anyway...
关于这个大恐龙，总之…
Hi.
嗨
- Ross, you remember Susan. - How could I forget?
- 罗斯，你记得苏珊 - 我怎么会忘记呢？
Ross.
罗斯
Hello, Susan. Good shake, good shake.
苏珊，握手力道蛮不错的
So, uh, we're just waiting for?
我们在等…
- Dr. Oberman. - Dr. Oberman. Okay, and is he...?
- 欧伯曼医生 - 欧伯曼医生，他是…
- She. - Of course, "she."
- 是她才对 - 当然，是她才对
She, uh, familiar with our special situation?
她知道我们的特殊状况吗？
Yes, and she's very supportive.
对，她非常支持我们
Great. Okay, that's great. Heh.
太棒了，那是件好事
No, I'm...
不，我…
CAROL: Thanks.
谢谢
Quack, quack...
呱…
...quack, quack, quack.
Ross?
罗斯
That opens my cervix.
那是用来打开我的子宫颈
- Barry? BARRY: Come on in.
- 贝瑞 - 请进
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
BARRY: It's fine, it's fine. Robbie's gonna be here for hours.
没关系，罗比得在这里待上几小时
Huh?
嗯？
So how are you doing?
你还好吧？
I'm...
我…
I'm okay.
我很好
You look great.
你气色很不错
Yeah, well...
没错
RECEPTIONIST [OVER SPEAKER]: Dr. Farber, Jason Greenspan's gagging.
巴巴尔医生 杰森·葛林斯潘笑个不停
Be right there. I'll be back in a second.
马上到，我立刻回来
I dumped him.
我甩了他
Okay.
好吧
Oh!
哦
- Ross. - So, um...? So how's this going to work...
- 罗斯 - 这应该怎么做才好？
...ahem, you know, with us?
我是说我们
You know, when, like, important decisions have to be made?
譬如说得做出重要决定时
Give me a "for instance."
举个例子来听听
Well, I don't know. Okay, okay.
我不知道，好吧
- How about with the baby's name? - Marlon...
- 宝宝的名字呢？ - 马龙
- Marlon. ...if it's a boy. Minnie, if it's a girl.
- 马龙 - 如果是儿子，女子就叫米妮
As in "Mouse"?
跟米妮老鼠一样？
As in my grandmother.
跟我奶奶一样？
Still, you say "Minnie," you hear "Mouse."
但提到米妮，大家会想到米妮老鼠
How about, um...
何不叫…
How about "Julia"?
何不叫茱莉亚呢？
Julia.
茱莉亚？
We agreed on Minnie.
我们同意叫米妮了
It's funny, um, we agreed we'd spend our lives together.
那真的很有趣 我们同意要共度一生
Things change. Roll with the punches.
事情变了，我们可以用拳头来决定
I believe Julia's on the table.
我相信茱莉亚是个好名字
Oh. Sorry about that.
对不起
So, what have you been up to?
你还好吧？
Oh. Not much.
还算可以
- I got a job. - Hey, that's great.
- 我找到工作了 - 那真的很棒
Why are you so tan?
为什么你皮肤变得这么黑？
Oh, I, uh...
我…
I went to Aruba.
我去了阿鲁巴
Oh, no. You went on our honeymoon alone?
不，你一个人去度我们的蜜月？
No.
不
See, uh, I went with...
听着，我跟…
- Now, this may hurt. - Me?
- 这或许会有点痛 - 我吗？
No.
不是
I went with Mindy.
我跟敏蒂去的
Mindy?
敏蒂？
My maid of honor, Mindy?
我的伴娘敏蒂？
Yeah, well, we're kind of a thing now.
对，我们在交往
Well, I'm...
我…
You got plugs.
你做了植发
Careful, careful. They haven't quite taken yet.
小心，它们还没有完全固定
And you got lenses.
你戴了隐形眼镜
But you hate sticking your finger in your eye.
你讨厌把手指戳到眼睛里
Not for her.
为了她，没关系的
Oh.
哦
Listen, I really wanted to thank you.
听着，我真的想谢谢你
Okay.
好的
About a month ago, I wanted to hurt you...
一个月前我想伤害你
...more than I've ever wanted to hurt anyone in my life.
你是我最想伤害的人
And I'm an orthodontist.
我是牙齿矫正师
Wow.
哇
You know, you were right. I mean, I thought we were happy.
你说得对，我以为我们很快乐
We weren't happy.
我们不快乐
But with Mindy...
可是跟敏蒂在一起
...now I'm happy.
现在我很快乐
- Spit. - What?
- 吐吧 - 什么？
Me.
是我
Anyway, um...
总之…
I guess, uh... I guess this belongs to you.
我想这该还给你
And thank you for giving it to me.
谢谢你把它送给我
Well, thank you for giving it back.
谢谢你把它还给我
Hello.
哈罗
Oh, please. What's wrong with Helen?
拜托，海伦有什么不好？
Helen Geller?
海伦·盖勒？
- I don't think so. - Hello, it's not gonna be Helen Geller.
- 我不觉得好 - 哈罗，宝宝不叫海伦·盖勒
Thank you.
谢谢
No. I mean, it's not Geller.
不，我是说宝宝不姓盖勒
What, it's gonna be Helen Willick?
什么？宝宝叫海伦·威利克？
No, actually, um, we talked about Helen Willick Bunch.
不，事实上她叫海伦·威利克·邦奇
Well, wait a minute. Why is she in the title?
等一下，为什么这跟她有关？
Because it's my baby too.
因为这也是我的宝宝
That's funny. Really? I don't remember you making any sperm.
那太好笑了，真的吗？ 我不记得你会制造精子
And we all know what a challenge that is.
我们都知道那是个多大的挑战
- Uh-huh. See? - All right, you two, stop it.
- 看吧 - 好了，你们两个，别说了
No, no. She gets a credit. Hey, I'm in there too.
不，她有功劳，我也是
Honestly. You're not actually suggesting Helen Willick Bunch Geller.
说真的，宝宝不能叫 海伦·威利克·邦奇·盖勒
I think that borders on child abuse.
我想那跟虐童差不多
Of course not. I'm suggesting Geller Willick Bunch.
当然不是 我想宝宝叫盖勒·威利克·邦奇
Oh, no. No, no, no. You see what he's doing?
不，你知道他在做什么吗？
He knows no one is gonna say all those names.
他知道没有人会那样叫她
He knows they'll wind up calling her Geller. Then he gets his way.
最后他们会叫她盖勒 那样子他就达到目的了
My way? You think this is my way?
我的目的？你觉得这是我的目的？
Believe me, of all the ways I ever imagined this moment in my life being...
相信我，目前我想像过的生活
...this is not my way. You know what? This is too hard.
绝对不包括这一点 你知道吗？这真的太难了
Knock, knock. How are we today? Any nausea?
还好吗？有恶心的感觉吗？
- A little. - Just a little.
- 有一点 - 只有一点
Well, I was just wondering about the mother-to-be, but, uh, thanks for sharing.
我是指准妈妈的感觉 不过谢谢你们跟我分享
Uh, lie back.
躺好
You know what? I'm gonna go.
你知道吗？我要走了
Um, I don't think I can be involved in this particular family thing.
我想我无法介入这种家务事
Oh, my God.
天啊
Look at that.
看看那个
I know.
我知道
Well, isn't that amazing?
那真的很神奇吧？
What are we supposed to be seeing here?
我们到底要看什么？
I don't know, but I think it's about to attack the Enterprise.
我不知道 我想那跟攻击企业号有关
You know, if you tilt your head to the left and relax your eyes...
如果你们的头往左斜，眼睛放轻松
...it kind of looks like an old potato.
它看起来像颗马铃薯
Then don't do that, all right?
别那么做，好吗？
Monica?
摩妮卡
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
Mm-hm.
嗯-哼
Are you welling up?
你哭了吗？
- No. - You are.
- 不 - 才怪
- You are. You're welling up. - No, I'm not.
- 才怪，你哭了 - 不，我才没有
- You're gonna be an aunt. - Oh, shut up.
- 你要当姑姑了 - 闭嘴
Hi, Mindy.
敏蒂
Hi, it's Rachel.
我是瑞秋
Yeah, I'm fine. I saw Barry today.
对，我很好，今天我跟贝瑞见面
Oh, yeah, yeah, he told me.
对，他跟我说了
No, it's okay. Really, it's okay.
不，没关系，真的
I hope you two are very happy. I really do.
我希望你们两个快乐，真的
And, Min, you know, if everything works out...
小敏，如果一切顺利
...and you guys end up getting married and having kids and everything...
你们会结婚生孩子
...I just hope they have his old hairline and your old nose.
我希望他们遗传了他的发线 跟你的鼻子
Okay, I know it was a cheap shot, but I feel so much better now.
好吧，我知道那么做很低级 但现在我觉得痛快多了